Hi and welcome to Learn WordPress. Inthis video, we are going to explore the
Columns block. The Columns block is acontainer block, which can be used to
create a variety of custom layouts, andit opens up a world of design
possibilities. The Columns block allowsyou to insert text, media and other
types of content into up to six columns.And when used one after another, the
Columns block creates a cool grideffect. To add a Columns block, click on
the Inserter and type columns or youcould type forward slash columns and
select it from there. You can choose thenumber and the size of the columns that
you want to start with. The beauty ofthe Columns block is that you can add
other blocks into each column. Forexample, you can create the Columns
block to add structure, and then addImage blocks, Heading blocks and
Paragraph blocks. You can also createthis type of design by adding a Cover
block to each column. There is aparent/child relationship between the
main Columns block and the individualcolumns that form part of the parent
block. When you click on the alignmenticon, you will be able to change the
alignment of your block to wide width orfull width. Did you know that you can
also duplicate columns? Let's select thethird column in the Columns block. When
you click on the three vertical dots,you have an option to duplicate.
Duplicating a design will save you a lotof time and effort. When you select an
individual column, you also have theoption in the block toolbar to use the
arrows to move the column to a newposition. But you also have the option
in the list view to drag and drop acolumn where you want. If you wanted to
add another column, you could merelyclick on the Inserter between two
columns to add a new column or you canselect the parent block and then open up
your sidebar settings. And at the top ofthe sidebar settings, you will notice it
says columns where you can increase ordecrease the amount of columns in your
Columns block. Then below that, keepstack selected if you want the columns
to stack on top of each other whenviewed on a mobile device. The Columns
block allows you to change the coloursof both the parent block or individual
columns. So let's go ahead and changethe background colour for example. There
are also various typography optionsworth exploring, such as font family,
appearance and letter spacing. You mighteven decide to change the size of your
Columns block.
Below dimensions you can adjust thepadding or the space around the content
of the block, and if you click on unlinksides, you can set different values for
the top, right, bottom and left. You canalso change the margin of the block,
which is the space surrounding theColumns block at the top and the bottom.
When you click on the ellipses, you canalso select Block spacing which allows
you to modify the space between columns.
Lastly, you may even decide to add aborder or change the radius of the
Columns block.
Another great feature is that you cantransform other blocks to a Columns
block and even a Columns block to aGroup block. So as you can see, you can
achieve any custom design using theColumns block from introducing your
team, displaying different types ofmedia or even creating a pricing table.
Enjoy designing with the Columns blockand visit Learn WordPress for more
tutorials and training material.