Welcome to Using the group block. Thegroup block allows you to group and
style multiple blocks together,simplifying content management and
design.
Learning Outcomes. How to set up a groupblock and add blocks. How to rename and
organize the list view. How to customizethe group block using settings and
styles option. Find documentation aboutthe group block.
Here is an example page that I want togo through first of some options of how
to use the group block. So the firstone, I use the group block with a
background image and a heading. I'vealso added a border and radius. The
second one, I used a group block with animage, heading and paragraph. Also added
a border around that. The third one,example is a group block with a heading
and a gallery block to create the page.
I've opened up a page, and I'm turned onmy list view, which is the three slashes
over in the upper left hand corner. Ilike to have my toolbar at the top. So
if you'd like to do this, you can clickon the three dots in the upper right
hand corner and go to top toolbar andturn that on. We're going to add a group
block. So I'll type in group with theslash. I'm just going to click on the
front the first one option, and then I'mgoing to go over to my styling tools.
I'm going to add my background image,open up my media library, make sure that
you've optimized your images beforeuploading them, and then add alt text
for accessibility. Now we're going to goand style our image so we have the group
block clicked. I'm going to go up intomy tools at the top and go to align, and
I'm going to do a full width on thealign. Okay, so now I'm going to go back
over to the right and go to the styles.I'm going to scroll down to minimum
height, and I want to add probably about644 let's try that maybe 645 because I
want to be able to get the hands inthere. So we'll start there and make
sure I click Update. And then anothertool that you can use is going back up
to the background, where you had thebackground image, and go to size and
open that up. So this gives you theoption to take the main focus and adjust
that so I can adjust that so that thehands are showing, and click update on
that. I'm going to then click on theplus sign within the group block and add
a heading. We make this baking. I'mgoing to click on the tools and go to
align text center. So we can't see thethe heading text very well. So I'm going
to do some styling on that. So I'm goingto go over to the styling tools and
click on background, and it opens up mymy colors, and I'm just going to pick
the green from here, and then I need toadd some padding. So I'm going to go
down to dimensions within the headingblock and turn on padding. I'm going to
do two clicks front and top and bottom,and two clicks side to side. I'm also
going to go back up to the group blockdo a little bit more styling there,
because I want a little bit of spacebetween the heading and the top. So I'm
going to go to styles, I'm going to addsome padding for the top and bottom so
that looks good. And then I'm going toadd my border. So I'm going to go down
to the border, I'm going to add thatsame green, and then I'm going to add a
little bit of thickness to it. And thenI'm also going to use the radius to show
you how to use that. So we're just goingto click on radius, and I'm going to a
radius adds a curve to the corner. SoI'm just going to make it very dramatic
and go all the way to 100 and we'regoing to click update, and we'll refresh
the page, and there's our first block.
For our second example, I'm going toclick on the three dots and do an add
after. This time, I'm not going to startwith a group block, because I want to
show you how to group blocks together.So let's start with an image. And we're
going to make this one a cookie one, andthen I'll add a heading. And I'm going
to grab some text from my example, and Iuse cupcake ipsum. It's a free site that
you can get filler text from, and thisone is just baking, so it's fun.
Alright, so we have our three blocksover here in our list view, and we can
click on the first one and then hitShift and click on the last one. And
once we have those highlighted, we'regoing to click on the three dots and we
can scroll down to the group. Okay, sothat was simple. Click Update, and then
we can go back on those three dots andclick rename, and keep our list view
organized. Okay, so let's go ahead andstop do some styling of this one. This
one, I'm going to do a line to a widewidth. Okay, give it a little bit
different in the layout. I'm going toturn off this just because I want the
text to be able to spread out a littlebit more. And we'll see when we get all
our styling done on that. I do want toclick on the image, because the image is
going to be a little bit big. It doesn'tauto with the original. So I'm going to
put in 568, because I want it a littlebit smaller. And then I want to align
this to this center. Okay, so we'llclick on that, click on the Update
button. And then I also want to add, goback up to our group block, and I want
to add a border around this so I'm goingto click on the colors and open that up
and just do a small border there. Clickon Update. I'm going to go up and add
some padding. So on this one, I want toadd about four clicks of padding, and
then two on the side. Let's do that. Andthen also, there's an option for this
block spacing. So I want to add a littlebit of space in between each of the
three blocks that I'm using. So we'll dothat. And I think I have everything.
Let's look at it on the front end. Clickand refresh. I forgot to align the text.
So let's go back to the header and we'llalign that to the center. There we go.
And we're good for that.
To add our last group block. I'm goingto click on the three dots from the
previous group and do an add after I'lltype in for a group block. I'll pick the
first option. I'm going to add aheading, and I'll style my heading to
align text center from the toolbar atthe top, and then I would add my gallery
here like that, but there is the examplehas Several different images. So to save
time, I'm going to do a quick back, backup. And what I'm going to do is just do
a copy and paste instead of adding allof the so I'm going to click on that
gallery, go to the three dots, and do acopy so I can add my images quickly. If
I open up the gallery block, you seethat they're all individual images.
Okay, so we're going to go back up toour group block. We would rename it. You
guys know how to do that. Now, on thisone, I'm going to make it a full width,
okay? And the other thing is to on mylayout for the group block. For this
one, I'm going to turn off this toggle,and this is going to make the images
spread out a little bit more. So makesure I click that update, because that's
a big update. I'm going to add abackground, so I'm going to click on the
styling, go to background and click onthe brown. I need a little bit of
padding here, so I'm going to go down topadding under dimensions and do two
clicks on the top and bottom and twoclicks on the side. We'll click update
on that. Think everything looks good.Fingers crossed everyone. We'll do a
refresh, and there we are.
See the resource section for the link todocumentation about the group block.
Have fun exploring all the ways to usethe group block. Thank you for watching.